wolftrap.org 2018-10-21

# Privacy Policy | Wolf Trap

This Privacy Policy sets forth the information practices of the Wolf Trap Foundation for the Performing Arts (the “Foundation,” “we” or “our”) with regard to patrons of the Foundation and users of the web sites owned or operated by the Foundation, including wolftrap.org 

This Privacy Policy constitutes a binding agreement between you, as a user of the web sites owned or operated by the Foundation (the “Sites”), and us, as the owner of the Sites. BY USING THE SITES, OR ACCESSING OR REGISTERING ON THE SITES, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT USE, ACCESS, OR REGISTER ON THE SITES.

**A. INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE  
**   
We collect two kinds of information from you: personal information that you choose to supply us and non-personal information such as your IP address. Specifically, we collect the following information:

  1. _**Personal Information.**_ As used in this Privacy Policy, the term "personal information" means both (i) information that specifically identifies an individual (such as first and last name or email address), and (ii) demographic, aggregate, or other information when it is directly linked to information that can identify an individual. For instance, if we collect your IP address (which is typically non-personal data) and tie it to your full name, the combination of this data would constitute “personal information.”
  2. _**Non-Personal Information.**_ We also may collect “non-personal information,” such as your IP address, device information (e.g., hardware model, operating system version, device identifier, and mobile network information), and/or data that is collected via cookies, web beacons, or other technical mechanisms. This information does not identify you personally, but it may provide us with information about your interests, your location, and the web sites, products, or services that you view and the time you spend viewing them.

We may also tie this non-personal information with personal information in order to provide you with better recommendations, to help authenticate you or other data or information that you may provide, to prevent fraud, and to ensure that the Sites meet your needs. When we tie non-personal information with personal information, it is considered “personal information” for the purposes of this Privacy Policy, and we will use and share this combined data in the ways described in Sections B and C of this Policy.

_NOTE: This Privacy Policy in no way restricts or limits our collection and use of non-personal information, and we may link this data to your personal information and/or share it with third parties for a variety of purposes, including to help us to better understand our customer needs, and to improve our Sites or for advertising and marketing purposes._

To learn how to opt-out of receiving further information about the Foundation, see the section marked "CHOICES" below. 

**B. HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION  
**   
The Foundation collects information in the following ways:  
**  
1\. Personal Information  **

>  ** _  
> a. Mailing Lists._** You may subscribe to our email mailing list, blog, or postal mailing list. To do so, we require that you provide your email address or your email address and a password (in the case of the blog or the email mailing list), or your name and mailing address (in the case of the postal mailing list). We will store the information you provide us in order to send you information about the Foundation. You may request to be removed from our email, blog, or postal mail mailing lists. 
> 
> **_b. Email._** If you submit feedback, questions or requests for information about our products and services, we may request your name, mailing address, telephone number and email address in order to respond to your inquiries. We may collect and store the information you provide us in order to send you information about our services. 
> 
> **_c. Surveys._** We may request information from you via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary; you have a choice whether or not to disclose any information to us. Information requested may include personal contact information such as your name, shipping address, phone number or email address. This information may be used to contact users with further information about products and services and for the purpose of monitoring or improving use of and satisfaction with the Sites. 
> 
> **_d. Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions._** We may request information from you when you choose to participate in contests, sweepstakes or other promotions. Participation in these sweepstakes or contests is completely voluntary; you have a choice whether or not to disclose any information. Information requested may include personal contact information such as your name, shipping address and email address. Contact information will be used to notify winners and to award prizes and in accordance with the rules for the promotion. 
> 
> **_e. My Wolf Trap._** In order to register for a My Wolf Trap account, we require that you provide your name, email address, mailing address, a user ID, and a password. We may use this information to provide you with breaking news, exclusive features, access to online ticket pre-sales, and other products and services. We may also tailor My Wolf Trap to you based on your use of the Sites, your status as a member of the Foundation, and your activities as a patron of the Foundation. 
> 
> _**f. Ticket Purchases, Gift Certificate Purchases, and Registration for Classes and Events Through the Foundation.**_ You may purchase tickets and gift certificates from the Wolf Trap Box Office. You may also register for and pay for classes and special events (such as dinners or member trips) through My Wolf Trap. In order to process ticket sales, gift certificate sales, class registrations, and special event registrations; to contact you regarding our services; and to better your experience, we may collect your name, email address, mailing address, credit card or debit card number, and other information (e.g. emergency contact information for children who are registered for classes, or dietary restrictions for special event dinners). We retain credit card and debit card numbers only as long as is necessary to process payment. If you make a pledge to the Foundation on a payment plan or sign up for a reoccurring donation, we will retain your credit card or debit card information as needed to process these payments. We are compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard, an industry standard for the protection of payment cardholder data.

>  _ **g. Ticket, Gift Certificate, and CD Purchases Through Third-Party Vendors.**_ The Foundation offers services for purchasing tickets, gift certificates, and CDs online from third party vendors. The Foundation also offers ticket sales by phone through a third party vendor. The Foundation does not process these orders or ship tickets, gift certificates, or CDs. When a visitor to our Sites purchases tickets, gift certificates, or CDs online, the visitor is taken to a website operated by the third party vendor. The Foundation does not dictate or supervise the information collection and use policies of any third party vendors. Review these third party vendors' privacy policies for more information on how your information may be collected and used. The Foundation may, however, access the data collected by third party vendors in order to contact you regarding our products or services.
> 
> _**h. Online Reservations for Ovations.**_ You may make reservations for Ovations, Wolf Trap’s onsite restaurant, online through a third party vendor. In order to facilitate your reservation, the Foundation may receive information that the third party vendor collects in connection with your use of its services. Again, the Foundation does not supervise the information collection and use policies of any third party vendor; review these vendors’ privacy policies for more information on how your information may be collected and used. 
> 
> _**i. Applications for the Wolf Trap Opera and for Other Programs, Events, and Internships.**_ If you apply to a program, event, or internship at the Foundation (e.g. the Filene Young Artist, Studio Artist, or Fellowship programs) – either online, by email, or through a PDF application – we may require that you provide information including, but not limited to, your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, birth date, resume, and eligibility for employment. This information may be used to evaluate your qualifications for the program, event, or internship and to contact you regarding the application process, auditions, callbacks and casting consideration, details and logistics for the program, event, or internship, and decisions as to acceptance.
> 
> _**j. Donations and Annual Memberships.**_ You may make donations to the Foundation or become a member of the Foundation through My Wolf Trap and other portions of the Sites. If you make a donation to the Foundation or become a member, we may collect certain information about you, such as your name, email address, mailing address, and credit card or debit card number. We retain credit card and debit card numbers only as long as is necessary to process payment. If you make a pledge to the Foundation on a payment plan or sign up for a reoccurring donation, we will retain your credit card or debit card information as needed to process these payments. We are compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard, an industry standard for the protection of payment cardholder data. In addition, see here for the Foundation’s donor-specific privacy policy on collection and use of personal information. 

>   
> 

**2\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information    
**

We may also collect non-personal information from you in the following instances: _  
_

> _a. Internet Protocol (IP) address._ Your IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send you data—such as the web pages you view. We may use this information to deliver our web pages to you upon request, to tailor the Sites to the interests of our users, and to measure traffic within the Sites 
> 
> _b. Cookies and Web Beacons._
> 
> We may use certain kinds of technology such as cookies and web beacons to collect information. Among other things, the use of cookies and web beacons enables us to improve our Sites by seeing which areas, features and events are most popular, to count the number of computers accessing our Sites, to personalize and improve your experience, to record your preferences, and to allow you to visit our Sites without re-entering your user name or password.   
>    
>  A cookie is a small amount of data which is sent to your browser from a web site's computer and stored on your computer's hard drive. Most browsers automatically accept cookies as the default setting. You can modify your browser setting to reject our cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie by editing your browser options. However, if a browser is set not to accept cookies or if a user rejects a cookie, some portions of our Sites may not function properly. For example, you may not be able to sign in and access certain web page features. Some of the cookies that we use may be flash cookies/Adobe cookies; these cookies may not be deleted when your cookies are deleted. If you are interested in altering your cookie settings, you should check your browser to determine where these types of cookies are stored and how they may be deleted.
> 
> A web beacon is an electronic image, also called a "gif," that may be in the form of a "png" image, as well as iframe, script, input link, embed, object, and other tags that are used to track usage. We may use these web beacons on our web pages to deliver cookies, attribute sales to our affiliate partners and advertisers, count visits, and compile statistics on usage and campaign effectiveness or in our emails to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.
> 
> We do not currently recognize “do not track” signals sent by browsers.  
>  **_  
> c. Geolocation Data_**. We may also collect your location if you choose to allow us to track your location through the Sites, or if your personal or non-personal information indicates a certain geographic location. This information may help us provide recommendations to you based on your location, serve you with advertisements, or direct you to event that we believe may be of interest to you and that is marketed to people near your location.  
>  **_  
> d. Google Analytics._** To help facilitate the delivery of relevant content, we utilize Google Analytics to identify how users engage with our Sites and to provide us with information regarding our users. Google provides a complete privacy policy and instructions on opting out of Google Analytics here: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html>. 

**C. SHARING OF INFORMATION  
**   
**1\. Personal Information  
**   
We may share your personal information with third parties as outlined in this Privacy Policy or with your consent. Below are examples of how we may share your personal information:

> a. We may disclose information to a third party (a) to comply with laws or respond to lawful requests and legal process, (b) to protect the Foundation, and our agents, customers, and others from legal claims or actions, including claims of fraud or to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use, or (c) in the good faith belief that disclosure is needed to respond to an emergency, or protect the personal safety of any person.
> 
> b. Our Sites may include collaboration features that by their nature support sharing with users you choose. Those users can see your name, email address, information you add to your profile, and any files you choose to share, and they can post comments and email you.
> 
> c. We may also share your personal information (either alone or in combination with non-personal information and/or demographic information) with affiliates, strategic partners, agents, third party publishers, retailers, and marketers, or other unaffiliated parties who are offering products or services that we believe may be of interest to you or who require your personal information for research, administrative, and/or internal business purposes. These parties may use this information to contact you with an offer or advertisement related to a product or service, or they may use such information for their own research, administration, or business purposes. ** _If you do not want us to share your personal information in this manner, do not provide us with this information._**
> 
> d. The Sites may provide you with opportunities to connect with third parties that may be publishing content and/or offering or advertising products and services. You may purchase products or services from these third parties or affiliates, while you are on the Sites. While these transactions will be between you and the third party, we may choose, or it may be necessary for us, to share your personal information with these parties in order to assist with the fulfillment of the transaction, as part of an agreement with that third party, or otherwise for the purposes described in this Section B(1) of the Privacy Policy. The Sites may also include access to social networking web sites established, owned, and controlled by third parties such as Facebook.com, and information may be exchanged between the Sites and these social networking web sites. If you choose to use any third party services or to access, purchase, or view products or services on a third party web site, we may facilitate sharing of your personal and non-personal information with those third parties. Your use of any services offered, or your purchase of any product offered by a third party, on a third party web site shall not be solely governed by our Terms of Use or this Policy and we do not control the services of those third parties or how they use your information. Be sure to review the terms and the privacy policies of those third parties before using their services.
> 
> e. We may be required to share your personal information in order to fulfill a service to you. For example, if you register on the Sites, we may need to share your personal and/or non-personal information with third parties in order to provide content to you that we believe may be of interest to you. Also, if you make a purchase through the Foundation or use the Sites to facilitate or consummate a purchase transaction, we may need to share your billing information with third party credit processing companies in order to fulfill such services for you. We also may need to share your personal information if you choose to enter a sweepstakes or contest in order to fulfill the terms of that promotion. This means that we may share the information for prize fulfillment purposes or with mail carriers. We also may share your information with the co-sponsor of any such promotion. We may need to share your information with unaffiliated third-party service providers, agents, or independent contractors who help us maintain the Sites and provide other administrative services to us (including, but not limited to providing customer service, maintaining, and analyzing data, sending customer communications on our behalf, and entry collection, winner selection and prize fulfillment for contests, sweepstakes and other promotions). We seek to ensure that these unaffiliated third parties will not use the personal information for any other purpose than to provide the administrative services for which they are responsible. Because these unaffiliated third-party service providers will have access to users' personal information, if you do not wish for these unaffiliated third-party service providers to have access to your information, do not register or submit any personal information to us.
> 
> f. We may share personal information in connection with an acquisition, merger, or sale of all or a substantial portion of our organization, with or to another company. In any such event, you will receive notice if your data is transferred and becomes subject to a substantially different privacy policy.
> 
> g. We may share personal information and/or non-personal information in order to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers and to provide such information to third parties.

**2\. Non-Personal Information, Aggregate Data, and Demographic Information  
**   
We reserve the right to share with our partners and advertisers any non-personal information about our customers, sales, and traffic. Also, we may share your non-personal information when it is tied to your personal information, as described in Section A of this Privacy Policy.

**D. CHOICE**

The Foundation provides you with the following choices regarding the use of your information: 

  * You may choose to not provide us with any personal information. However, if you do so, we will be unable to sign you up for our email, blog, or postal mail mailing lists; register you for a My Wolf Trap account; register you for classes; process your application for the Filene Young Artist, Studio Artist, or Fellowship programs; register you as a member of the Foundation; or enter you into any sweepstakes or contests. Additionally, your ability to navigate the Sites may be impaired. 
  * To opt-out of receiving further information from us and be removed from our online mailing list, visit <http://www.magnetmail.net/actions/subscription_manage_wolftrap.cfm> and follow the 'Unsubscribe' procedure, or email us at [wolftrap@wolftrap.org](mailto:wolftrap@wolftrap.org). 
  * To change or modify information you have previously provided us for the postal mailing list, send an email to [wolftrap@wolftrap.org](mailto:wolftrap@wolftrap.org). 
  * To opt-out of receiving further blog posts from the Foundation, follow the “Unsubscribe” instructions in the emails notifying you of blog posts, or email us at [wolftrap@wolftrap.org](mailto:wolftrap@wolftrap.org).
  * If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the information practices of the Foundation, please contact:

Wolf Trap Foundation for the Performing Arts  
1645 Trap Road  
Vienna, Virginia 22182  
Attn: Privacy Policy

**E. NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES  
**   
We may make changes to the Privacy Policy. When we do, we will update the “last updated” date below. If we decide to make a material change our Privacy Policy, we will post a notification on our homepage to draw your attention to the change. 

**F. SPECIAL POLICY WITH REGARD TO INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN UNDER THIRTEEN  
**   
The Sites are not targeted to children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from any child under the age of 13 without parental consent. When we do receive such information, we delete it as soon as we discover it and we do not use it or share it with third parties. 

**G. SECURITY  
**   
No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us, and you understand that any information that you transfer to us is done at your own risk.

We take reasonable steps to protect information that we collect from you in order to try to prevent loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. If we learn of a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the Sites or providing personal information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Sites. You understand and agree that we may post a notice on our Sites if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing via ordinary mail.

If you have any questions about the security of our Sites, please contact [wolftrap@wolftrap.org](mailto:wolftrap@wolftrap.org).

**H. THIRD PARTY WEB SITES**

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Foundation. The Sites may provide links to third party web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other web sites.

**I. FORUMS, CHAT ROOMS, AND OTHER POSTING AREAS  
**   
Any information you include in a message that you post to any chat room, forum, or other posting area on the Sites is available to anyone with Internet access able to access those portions of the Sites. If you don't want people to know your email address, for example, don't include it in any message you post. BE EXTREMELY CAREFUL WHEN DISCLOSING ANY INFORMATION IN CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS AND OTHER POSTING AREAS ON THE SITES. WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE INFORMATION THAT YOU DISCLOSE IN CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS, AND OTHER POSTING AREAS.

**J. PASSWORD  
**   
Your account information and access to our Sites are sometimes accessible only through the use of an individual user ID and password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. Advise us immediately if you believe that the confidentiality of your password has been compromised or that your password has been misused. In addition, always log out and close your browser when you finish your session. We will never ask you to disclose your password in an unsolicited phone call or email.

**K. ASSIGNMENT  
**   
In the event that all or part of our assets are sold or acquired by another party, or in the event of a merger, you grant us the right to assign the personal and non-personal information collected via the Sites and via your patronage of or visits to the Foundation.

Effective Date: February 18, 2015  
Last Updated: February 18, 2015
